Hello friends, I am Ram Singh Yadav and
welcome to February. So friends, in this video
I am going to discuss about Care
Health Insurance. Specifically, I will
discuss this company. Should
you trust this company or yours? Because when
you are buying health insurance, then
whatever plan you buy, you always think long term.
You do
n't think that I have bought a plan for two-three years and
later I will go to some other company.
Most of the plans are
not that late. So, if you are one of those who has a
long term vision and is thinking of a long
term plan in this company, then
you will definitely have to watch this video completely. Because
if you have not seen it, then
you can also get lost. Because nowadays things are
going very smoothly in the market. That is why I am
saying this because if you do
not know anything well and you are being
sold everything without explaining some things
properly, then it is called a kind of
misselling, but they mean that there is
a Bengaluru
misselling happening, now in the front.  You don't even realize that it doesn't matter that much. You do
n't have the option of sealing with you. In this video, I will try to
tell you everything that can happen to you too. If you are
thinking of getting a new health insurance plan,
especially online.
Go to any website from any platform and
enter your number and you get a call directly from
customer care. Their system works in
this way and you are
called repeatedly to explain the plan to you.
And I will talk specifically about
Policy Bazaar, which is his personal
favorite, which is the Care
Advantage Plan and Care
Supreme Plan from Care Health Insurance. You must have also experienced it.
If you have, then let me know
in the comments section so that more people can know about it.
Then in second place is
their Niwabua's Supreme Plan and it is always
said that this is the most affordable
plan and it has many features inside it. No other
company in the market is giving you such features. This price
tag is also correct. You should go and compare it
yourself at Policy Bazaar.  When you check the
policy, I am taking the name of the head because
mostly it
is very famous and people know this thing, there are
two-three more as well, you do a paper comparison in the beginning, you keep
our plans
on the side, now you see, then later you
see the premium, okay this premium is very low for
curry or it is not that of papa and in the
plan that is being provided to you, a
lot of features are given behind it, you
compare it with some other plan, then you come to know that
oh man other plan so like
in this price tag, they are giving very less sum in short,
you are being given very less thing
and you think that man you are not getting money on value,
where do you get money on value,
you are getting it in tax, you are getting it on Saturday,
why because there you
get three x five x 10x all these good things which seems to be a very attractive team, it
attracts a lot, you will get
shirt by paying very less money, I did not claim for two years, did
not claim for five years, did
not claim for 10 years
My insurance of Rs 10 lakh will easily become Rs 1
crore, so this is the vision that
we plan everything, most of the
people do this, I personally get
calls on my personal number and I get
complaints like this that they have made this plan
for thinking or they are making this plan, when
I ask that this plan is
told to you directly, the policy market people did
not tell me, so I also thought and bought it, so
my only problem is that when you
try all these things online, the policy, all these
things have come, then you are told only incomplete
things, they say that
this is the best plan, it is the most
affordable in the market, but the
problem is that it is
not the best for the long term, it is not affordable for the long term, the
problem is just this because if you
look specifically, if I talk about the advantage,
what is the advantage, then its all
inside I think so 25% starts
and its premium can be
compared with any plan,
you will not get a plan more affordable than this in the entire market,
in the entire care list, if
you  Even if you check, you won't find it. The plan I'm
showing you is for a couple,
both from 28 Years of Asia and
for Mumbai. The first thing you'll see in this search result is that there are
some plans here that
come with the name Direct. Direct is written before any plan,
like Care Supreme
Direct or Care
Advantage Direct. Now, what does this Direct mean?
Direct means that the
plan is the same, but in Direct, you're
given a 5% discount on the plan,
and the premium is also shown to you in this way. The same
plan is
listed in two ways, one with discount and one
without discount. There's no difference because on
every website online, if you see a 5%
discount, the majority of insurances
give you. If you carefully look at the premiums of all, then first of all, the
Direct Care plan is
13,000. All other plans are
comparatively higher than that. Care Plus is
also being shown higher, which is 19,000.
If I talk about the Care Plus plan in terms of
So this Last Air is one of the best from here
but now it is
not the best because Care Supreme and Care
Advantage have gone. Still, if you look at the
premiums of all of them today, the
premium of Supreme and Care Advantage is comparatively the
lowest among those 12 plans. What
is the reason, so can you get trapped in that plan?
Last Air's plan was Care Plus.
Its premium is also
higher than Care Advantage and Care Supreme. You might think
that you are sounding too good.
So the problem is that
they have launched a new plan and
not many people are associated with this plan,
so
what will they do by trapping people? Once people
enter the plane, fill the bus with people and take the policy of
Next Air. Whatever it is, they
increase it directly from the gate by around 5650% and
this does
not increase even that much, at least by a minimum of
35%. So, they easily increase the premium for
free, that is, this becomes affordable. Today the
premium which is getting cheaper than most of the people.
You are getting the best features at such a cheap rate,
then when the time comes for the next air renewal, then
this premium will become affordable, the
value which you were
paying today will become like north so
good for you tomorrow, or the next to
next air will be there and you will see that the
premium of all the companies increases, yes it
increases due to inflation,
but it increases by 5%, 10%, but there is
no direct increase of 25-30% for any
plane, and you can see here all the 12 plans of Sona Kari,
some of them are
direct plans, which are
just direct plans, they are given with 5%
discount, but the
problem is that
despite being the best plane of Kari, despite having all the features,
why is it being given cheap, I just want you to
answer this in the comment
area below, why is this being given, is the
company very fond of us
or is it giving you this plane at a cheap rate
or is the company taking a long term decision,
no, the company is just
targeting people  So today there are a lot of people in this plane of debt.
Once a fund is formed,
whatever their target is, after that they will
directly increase the premium. Whatever
its actual premium is, they will increase it
later. This planning will become affordable. You will have
only two options left.
After taking the time of black moment, here you can move
to some other company which will be cheaper for you
or you can pay higher premium
or the third option is that you can also
move to a cheaper plane in this company itself.
When you change the plane in the company,
it is called migration. If you change to another company, it is
called portability.
So this is the option available. If you
port, then the company gets 100% benefit on the front because
you did not do that also and
gave a lot of your money to the company
in the pursuit of discount, then
in the pursuit of cheapness or in the pursuit of value for money, you
migrated your phone and
moved to some other plane in the company, then it is
only beneficial for the company because you are still associated with the company
and are ready to give the third option, then it
is beneficial for the company.
Because
you are paying the value of the plane, so the company will not suffer any loss, so the
company is reducing it in this way at the moment,
I personally felt that I should
tell you people and once these
people who say that the claim settlement
ratio of this company is very good, the rate of this company is
low, then I will search for a good one, the
claim settlement ratio of this company is 99%,
I should go with this, if its claim is 95% then the claim
settlement ratio, then I should
avoid this, so tell me
what does 99% claim settlement ratio mean, it
means that out of 100 people, the
claims of 99 people have been passed, only
one person's claim has been rejected,
for this, the claim settlement ratio of a particular company is
99%,
I am talking about it as an example, so mother, you have taken your
plane, the
claims of 99 people have been passed, the claim settlement ratio of one person has been rejected.  Here is my
personal number, you can directly
contact me. My charges are there.
Now many people will say that this is too
much, so this is better than your sledging
policy which you take.
Apart from this, if
you do something wrong and suppose tomorrow it does
not happen or you port it or
you migrate, then that too will
not happen. Whatever 10, 15, 20 thousand rupees you spend on it,
it would have been completely wasted. So
instead, give me 499 rupees and I will give you the best suggestion,
I will give you the best advice.
I will groom all the terms and conditions well,
how everything works.
Many of my videos will already be good,
so you must have got an idea about the
level of understanding I will give you
regarding your policy and one more thing I would
like to tell you which no one talks about is the
claim rates. Now you will ask
what is this, then I will tell you the way in which claim
settlement rates are done, in which it has been
found out that how many people  The claim was passed,
what percentage of people's
claims were rejected,
in the claim settlement ratio, the income ratio
tells how much money the company has and
how much it has earned, debt ratio, how much premium the company collected from these people, put
it
in the entire financial year and how much money an individual
claim owes to people, if the company has
deposited Rs. 100 crore in premium
from all the people in the financial year
and Rs. 90 crore has been given after the claim,
because claims also come, if the premium is taken then the
claim will have to be paid and the Rs. 10 crore that is
returned is managed by the company itself,
this is also important in running the entire business because
if the company gives back 100% in claims
then it will not run the business and the business
model will completely collapse, so the
insurance company reduces it in a systematic manner, so
you people should look at the claim settlement ratios,
but
also look at the incurrence claim ratios because from which it is known
how much premium the company is collecting
and how much money it is distributing and  If I
specifically talk about Care Health Insurance, then
you get to see some such data. No
one told you this thing
that Care Health Insurance has an
in-credit claim ratio of 55% in 20-21. This
means that brother, if the company
took 100% money, whatever the amount would be,
they distributed only 55% of that amount. Out of that,
45% went into running the entire business
and the rest is considered as profit.
And if I talk about 21-22, then the
company distributed 65%. Out of 100,
65% was distributed and the rest was used for
profit and
running the entire business. Now you will say,
friend, is this more or less, but you are comparing,
friend, you will know from other companies.
If you look at Star Health, Star has
distributed 94% out of 100 claim money.
We should talk about money, not the number of people. The
matter is about the number of people.
Claims  In settlement ratio, if we talk about in-
coordinated claim ratio, which no one talks about, then if we
talk about the star, then here
they have distributed 90% out of 100,
sir, claims means people are being given claims in
abundance and
if I talk about 2122, then
87% is their enclave, brother, 187%
they collected, the entire amount that was collected has been given,
now brother, well,
where are they printing so much money, do you care about your life,
friend, people say that it is a
very good company, it is very important, it is
making very good plans, so this is the only
reason that no
one tells about all these things in the background and no
one even tells because no one does any calculation at all, to
calculate this you have to
read all the things, this is what I am
telling you from the book, the annual reports from PF, IRDA,
Azim, of the entire
health insurance, no one discusses this, if
someone starts telling you this without telling you  I
gave it to you, brother, so friend, you will
not be sold by their plan, then brother, the
company is paying a premium, everyone has a battery worth money,
but very few people are
running away from here, once you buy it, you
realize after two or three years that
I made a mistake, and that's what I was saying, there is
leading sale, you are sold,
but
these people do not consider that there is this kind of
misdirection also because it is
always the duty of the advisor to tell you everything in
advance, so if you
want to take my financial, then definitely
499, yes, promotion is earned, friend, because
after giving so much information, if you are
not supporting me, then you
understand the meaning of such content, friend, at least give
a like for this thing, you will not be
able to call, and it's good, but one like is earned, it has
come from you people that you will get it, and
brother, my personal consolidation is always on,
you can take personal consolidation for me on this number,
and
I have already made many videos of mine.  So
you can go and see directly all the terms and
conditions which I felt like pointing out,
I have pointed them out, there is always
limited time, for this I have
tried to make this video of 10 to 12 minutes, I
hope you liked all this
and if you have any doubt or want to ask something then let
me know and leave a comment below and if you
liked the video then please like
and subscribe to the channel, thank you for
watching this video.